[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：让我们评估一下我们在这个研讨会中都做了哪些工作。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Let's take stock of where we've been through this workshop.
我们已经讨论了太多了。
There's an awful lot that we've gone over.
从开头的回调开始。
Started at the beginning with callbacks.
查看了回调的缺点和缺点
Looked at the disadvantages, the shortcomings of callbacks and
想想召回地狱，就是这个概念。
thinking about the call back hell, it's this notion of.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：控制反转和非局部和非顺序推理。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Inversion of control and non-local and non-sequential reasoning.
我们看了thunks，他们真的没有任何解决方案。
We looked at thunks, and they didn't really have any solutions to that.
但雷声至少给了我们一个概念上的支撑
But thunks at least gave us a conceptual underpinning for
与时间无关的值。
values that are time independent.
去除时间作为一种状态复杂性。
Removing time as a state complexity.
砰的一声，我们开始讨论许诺。
Thunks led us into our discussion of promises.
而且承诺不仅是这样，而且它们也是反转的解决方案
And promises are not only that, but they are also a solution to inversion of
控件，因为它们的构建方式旨在创建可信任的系统和
control because the way they're built is designed to create a trustable system and
围绕回调行为方式的可预测系统。
predictable system around the way callbacks are behaving.
发电机，发电机是正在解决的回调地狱的另一部分，
Generators, generators are the other part of callback hell being solved,
为我们提供了一个本地化的可暂停堆栈。
giving us a localized pauseable stack.
使用本地堆栈执行和本地错误处理之类的东西。
With local stack execution and local error handling and that sort of thing.
所以我们现在有分块顺序同步查找代码，
So we now have blocking sequential synchronous looking code,
在幕后被分解掉，异步性正在发生。
that under the covers is factored away, that the asynchronicity is happening.
太棒了。
Those are great.
这是我们的基线。
That's our baseline.
但是我们会说我们如何去适应基于事件的编程，
But then we say well how are we gonna to adapt an event based programming,
因为我们在现代复杂API中处理了很多事件。
cuz there are lots of events that we deal with in modern complex APIs.
嗯，事实证明，观察是一种很好的方法。
Well, turns out observables are a great way of doing it.
我们看了一个轻量级版本的观察表，我称之为
We looked at a lightweight version of observables that I call
反应序列。
reactive sequences.
最后，CSP GO例程有点像，如果观察值刚刚结束
Finally the CSP go-routines is kind of like, if observables are just over
地平线，CSP是紧随其后的东西。
the horizon, CSP is the thing that's coming on right behind it.
所以几年后每个人都会想哇，
So a couple years from now everybody's going to be thinking wow,
为什么我不早点上CSP的火车。
why didn't I get on the CSP train earlier.
所以，我们已经走了很长一段路，我想用幻灯片表达的观点是，
So, we've come a long way, and the point that I wanna make with the slide is,
此列表中没有一个项目可以替代列表中的所有其他项目。
there's no one item on this list that replaces all the other items on the list.
没有银弹。
There's no silver bullet.
没有一样东西。
There's no one thing.
我不时听到这样的话。
I hear this from time to time.
我听到反应式编程世界的人说，为什么我需要承诺，
I hear people in the reactive programming world say, why do I ever need a promise,
因为我可以用一个可观测的模型来模拟一切。
cuz I can model everything with an observable.
我听到CSP世界的人说，
And I hear people in the CSP world saying,
为什么我需要一个可观察的，因为我可以用流建模一切。
why do I ever need an observable cuz I can model everything with the stream.
我认为这是一种非常不成熟、天真的看待我们正在做的事情的方式。
I can see that to be a very immature, naive way of looking at what we're doing.
所以这个研讨会的原因。
So the reason for this workshop.
本研讨会存在的原因是向您展示所有这些不同的工具，以及
The reason this workshop exists is to show you all of these different tools, and
让你带着更好的欣赏离开
to have you come away with a better appreciation for
它们都符合我们正在建设的更大的计划。
where they all fit in in the bigger scheme of what we're building.
从现在开始，这里没有一个工具会成为你的解决方案。
No one tool here is gonna be your solution from now on.
但是所有这些工具的收集，是一个重大的飞跃，
But the collection of all these tools, is a significant jump forward,
不只是一点点。
not just a little bit.
但是订单的大小向前跳跃
But orders a magnitude jump forward for
在程序中表达显示异步编码的能力。
your ability to expressively show asynchronous coding in your programs.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：为了真正把这一点牢牢敲定，我建造了，所以
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So to really hammer that point home, I built, so
我不知道为什么我点击了逃逸。
I don't know why I hit escape.
几周前我做了一个东西并发布了它，
I built a thing a couple of weeks ago and released it,
这叫三张名单的故事。
it's called A Tale of Three Lists.
我会给你看这个演示，但让我告诉你这个东西存在的原因。
I'm gonna show you this demo, but let me tell you why this thing exists.
有人听说过To Do MVC项目吗？
Anybody ever heard of the to do MVC Project?
你们中的一些人可能正在点头，你们听说过。
Some of you are probably nodding your heads, you've heard of it.
做MVC的意义是什么，每个人都有自己的特别之处
What was the point of to do MVC was, everybody that has their own special
他们这样的框架是神奇的银弹。
framework that they're like this is the magical silver bullet.
他们有机会使用自己的代码解决完全相同的问题。
They got an opportunity to solve the exact same problem using their code.
现在你有，我甚至不知道有多少像30，40，100，000，
Well now you have, I don't even know how many like 30, 40, 100,000,
谁知道那里提交了多少项目。
who knows how many projects that have been submitted there.
每个人都有自己特殊的独角兽框架，
Where everybody who has their own special unicorn framework,
要炫耀他们做[INAUDIBLE]的方式，好吗？
gets to show off the way they do it to do [INAUDIBLE] okay?
但是异步编程呢？
But what about asynchronous programming?
我决定开始并创建用于异步编程的to do MVC。
I decided to set out and create the to do MVC for asynchronous programming.
这就是三张单子的故事。
And that's what a tale of three lists is.
这是一个稍微复杂一点的东西，而不仅仅是一个fubar的东西。
It's a slightly more complex than just a fubar kinda thing.
它更复杂，因为当我给你看演示时，
It's more complex cuz when I show you the demo,
到处都是活动，停顿之类的。
there's events firing all over the place, and pauses and stuff like that.
但后来我又七次实施了同样的演示，
But then I went and implemented the same demo seven different times,
使用七种不同的异步模式。
using seven different asynchronous patterns.
我们在这个工作坊里学过的东西，
The stuff that we've gone over in this workshop,
我实现了相同的代码库，并排，七种不同的方式。
I implemented the same code base, side by side, seven different ways.
我愿意接受其他可能有其他模式的人的贡献
And I'm open to contributions from others who may have other patterns that
有相对的长处和短处。
have relative strengths and weaknesses.
但关键是我们现在有七个并排的代码库做完全相同的事情
But the point is we now have seven side by side code bases doing exactly the same
任务，但是不同的方法有不同的优势和
task, but different ways with different strengths and
弱点，作为一种学习工具。
weaknesses, as a learning tool.
这就是我想要的。
And that's what I wanna get across.
如果你还没有听到我说的其他话，你可以通过
If you haven't heard anything else I've said, be able to go through and
说我看到诺言是如何运作的，然后我来了
say I see how the promises one works, and then I come and
看看可观测的那一个，我看到了更强大的地方。
look at the observables one, and I see places where that's much more powerful.
但是会有一些地方的观察者有一些尴尬的地方。
But there'll be places where the observables have some awkwardness.
所以我们可以去看CSP，然后说，
And so we can go and look at the CSP one and say,
哇，CSP在这方面比可观测的更好。
wow the CSP one is better at that than the observables one.
值得注意的是，找到最好的工具
And the take away is, find the best tools for
您的应用程序的任何给定部分，并成熟地应用它们。
any given part of your application and apply them maturely.
所以，让我向你展示演示非常快。
So, let me show you the demo real quick.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：顺便说一下，这是回购。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: This is the repo by the way.
所以我积极欢迎其他人提交和改进东西。
So I'm actively open to other people submitting and improving things.
但这里是演示，这是使用回调的那个。
But here is the demo, and this is the one using callbacks.
但他们的行为都完全一样，所以。
But they all behave exactly the same, so.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：那么这是什么，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So what this is,
有一个制作人每隔50毫秒就产生一次消息，而且
is there is a producer that's producing messages every 50 milliseconds, and
我有两个不同的侦听器，它们以不同的速度对流进行采样。
I have two different listeners that are sampling that stream at different speeds.
所以在这里，我每隔900毫秒就采样一次，s或什么的
So over here I'm sampling at once every I think 900 millisecond,s or something and
每600毫秒过来一次。
over here every 600 milliseconds.
我不记得数字是什么了。
I don't remember what the numbers are.
但我正在以不同的速度对它们进行采样，并将它们打印到这个列表中。
But I'm sampling them at different speeds and printing them into this list.
除了以不同的速度对它们进行采样之外，我还在收听
In addition to them being sampled at different speeds, I'm also listening to
单击这些，当您单击该项目时，它会将其添加到您的中心列表中。
clicks on these, and when you click on the item it adds it to your center list.
所以所有这些流或在所有这些不同的时间发射，
So all of these streams or firing at all these different times,
另外，如果有一个重复的，它会从我们的列表中被标记掉。
and in addition if there's a duplicate it gets marked off of our list.
所以这只是随机产生所有这些不同的
So this is just randomly generating all these different
正在添加到列表中的消息。
messages that are being added to the list.
现在你好像天啊，我收到太多信息了。
Well now you're like well jeez, I'm getting too many messages.
我需要暂停一下。
I need to pause.
因此您可以暂停一个或两个列表。
So you can pause one or both of the lists.
当您暂停两个列表时，
And when you pause both of the lists,
现在，正在制作该消息的制作人停止了制作。
now the producer who is producing that message, he stops producing.
因为如果他继续制作
Because if he kept producing and
没有人在消费，好吧，现在你会浪费大量的电池电量。
nobody was consuming, well now you'd be wasting crazy amounts of battery power.
因此，它等待消费者暂停和
So, it waits for both consumers to be paused and
它停止生产，然后一旦其中一个开始再次消费，
it stops producing, and then once one of them starts consuming again,
他开始每50毫秒发送一次。
he starts sending them out every 50 milliseconds.
所以，我想说的是，如果我拿出一个CSP的例子。
So, the point that I'm making is if I were to pull up the CSP one for example.
这里的行为完全相同，但使用CSP语义实现。
It's the exact same behavior here but implemented with CSP semantics.
所以如果我们运行CSP One
So if we run the CSP one.
如果我暂停这两个列表，应用程序中没有发生任何事情。
If I pause both of these lists, and there's nothing happening in the app.
我们应该能够打开并做一个配置文件，一个JavaScript CPU配置文件。
We should be able to open up and do a profile, a JavaScript CPU profile.
我们应该能够看到什么都没有发生，因为一切都发生了
And we should be able to see that nothing is happening because everything has
暂停了。
been paused.
在CSP中这非常简单，因为如果没有人消费
And in CSP that's super easy, cuz if nobody is consuming
那么你尝试推出什么东西多少次都无关紧要，对吧？
then it doesn't matter how many times you try to push something out, right?
所以我在CSP实现中免费获得了这个部分。
So that part I got for free with the CSP implementation.
而对于回调，您必须做更多的工作。
Whereas with the callbacks you had to do a lot more work.
但让我们快速收集CPU配置文件。
But let's collect the CPU profile real quick.
在我说话的时候，我会让它运行几秒钟。
And I'll just let it run for a couple of seconds as I'm talking.
在页面的背景中没有发生任何事情，所以
Nothing's happening in the background of the page, so
我们应该期待基本上是一个空的侧写。
we should expect basically an empty profile.
你会注意到空闲是唯一发生的事情。
And you'll notice that idle was the only thing that was happening.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：[咳嗽]如果你看一下Delta，回调之间的差异
&gt;&gt; Kyle: [COUGH] If you look at the delta, the difference between the callback
实施，以及CSP实施。
implementation, and the CSP implementation.
要实现同样的能力，需要做更多的工作。
It takes a whole lot more work to make that same capability happen.
因此，这是一个比大多数人展示异步性更复杂的演示。
So this is a more sophisticated demo than most people show off asynchronicity.
我想这么做的原因是，很容易错过重要的
And the reason I wanted to do that is, it's really easy to miss the important
当您有琐碎的，hello world示例时的详细信息。
details when you have trivial, hello world examples.
所以我想要更复杂的东西，
So I wanted to have something that's more sophisticated,
看起来更像现实世界。
more real world looking-ish.
也许没有to-do应用程序那么复杂，但它
Maybe not quite as sophisticated as a To-Do app, but it's
从事件和异步编程的角度更接近真实世界。
more real world-ish from the perspective of events and asynchronous programming.